iafstore.com 2017-02-07

# IAFSTORE - Customer Care - Privacy Policy

**Optional or compulsory communication of personal data**

Communicating your personal data to IAFSTORE when requested in any of the many instances where personal data is collected through the site may be essential in order to achieve the purposes set down by the communication itself, or not prejudicial in this regard.  
The compulsory or optional nature of the data provision is specified each time – with reference to the specific data requested – at the point of input for each data collection, by marking compulsory information with an asterisk (*).  
If you refuse to communicate the information marked as compulsory to IAFSTORE, it will be impossible to achieve the main purpose of the specific data collection: such a refusal might, for example, make it impossible for IAFSTORE to fulfill the product sale agreement on IAFSTORE.COM or provide the other services available on IAFSTORE.COM (assistance, forwarding of the IAFNEWS newsletter).  
Communicating additional data to IAFSTORE, other than those marked as compulsory, is optional and will not produce any consequences with regard to the main purposes of the collection (such as using the web site and its services or purchasing the products on sale, for example).

**Data supervisors**

Currently some of the data supervisors charged with processing your personal data are the following:

United Parcel Service, BRT S.p.A. that processes the data required to organise and carry out shipment, delivery and return of products purchased on our web site;

**Your rights**

You are entitled, at any time, to obtain confirmation from IAFSTORE that your personal data is or is not being processed, even if not yet registered, and its communication in an intelligible form.  
You are also entitled to obtain information from IAFSTORE about the source of your personal data, the purposes and methods of data processing that apply to your personal data; the type of logic applied when electronic instruments are used for data processing; full identification of the data controller and data supervisors; the names of the persons or categories of persons to whom personal data may be communicated or who may become privy to personal data while performing their duties as, by way of example, the data supervisors. All this information is included in this Privacy Policy.

In addition, you may always be entitled to obtain from IAFSTORE:  
updating, correction and integration of your personal data;

cancellation, transformation into an anonymous form or the blocking of your personal data if processed in violation of the law, including the data deemed unnecessary for the purposes for which the data was collected or subsequently processed in the first place;

certification that the operations described at letters a) and b) have been notified, even with regard to their contents, to the persons to whom your data has been communicated or disseminated, except in those instances where such certification turns out to be impossible or would require a clearly disproportionate deployment of means compared to the right protected.

You do, in any case, have the right to totally or partially oppose:lower-alpha

processing of your personal data, for valid reasons, even if pertinent to the purpose of collection;

the processing of your personal data for the purposes of advertisement or direct marketing mailings, or if used for the purposes of market surveys or commercial communications.

You may freely exercise your rights at any time by sending a written request to IAFSTORE – to the mailing address or to the e-mail address info@iafstore.com - and we will reply promptly.  
To ensure that your personal data is always exact, up to date, pertinent and complete, please advise us of any variations by writing to info@iafstore.com.

Art. 130, paragraph 4, Legislative Decree 196/2003

We wish to inform you that the law regulating protection of personal data permits IAFSTORE – without any obligation to obtain your prior consent – to use your data for direct selling activities involving products similar to those you have already purchased, unless you refuse to allow such use of the e-mail address you communicate to us.

Italian Privacy Authority Provision of 19 June 2008 on simplification of requirements for processing operations for administrative or accounting purposes

We also wish to inform you that the Italian Privacy Authority's provision permits IAFSTORE to use your postal address for sending you - with administrative and accounting documents - adverts about products similar to those you have already purchased, unless you refuse to allow such use of the postal address you communicate to us.

All of the above constitute the minimum information that IAFSTORE is obliged to provide you with: for any further information about processing of your personal data by IAFSTORE, we invite you to read this entire Privacy Policy.

**A summary of our privacy policy**

The principles on which our privacy policy is based are listed below:  
process data exclusively for the purposes and according to the methods illustrated in the notice presented to users at the time of its collection;

use data for other purposes, with respect to those specified at the time of collection, only where the user has expressed its express consent to such use;

make data available to third party companies only for purposes that are strictly necessary to provide the requested service(s) and only where monitored by a data supervisor; not communicate, cede or transfer data to third parties for purposes exclusive to the third party unless the users have received prior warning and have granted their consent;

answer all requests for cancellation, variation and integration of personal data, opposition to data processing for the purpose of sending commercial information and advertising;

ensure that data processing is conducted fairly and legally, protecting user privacy and implementing appropriate measures for security and protection of the privacy, integrity and availability of the data provided by users.

**Cookies**

See our cookie policy at: /customer-care-cookie-policy

Our site uses automatic systems to collect data that is not directly communicated by the user, such as cookies. A cookie is an application transmitted to the user’s hard disk; it does not contain any comprehensible information but associates the user with the personal information registered on the web site. Cookies are stored on our server and no one has access to the information they contain. Only IAFSTORE processes the information collected through cookies, only in anonymous and aggregate status, in order to optimize our services and our site in relation to the specific requirements and preferences of our users.  
Internet browsers have a function that makes it possible to cancel cookies after each session. The browser provides instructions on the cancellation procedure. Familiarise yourself with it.  
Acceptance of automatic data collection and use of cookies are both necessary to make use of the site and its services, including online sales. If you have activated cookie cancellation, IAFSTORE cannot guarantee that you will have access to full visualization of certain web pages, or be entitled to obtain certain services, such as for example the memorisation and visualisation, on given web pages, of the products you have selected during the process of online buying.

**Jurisdiction**

This Privacy Policy is regulated by Italian law and, in particular, by the code governing protection of personal data (Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30 June 2003), which regulates treatment of personal data – including data stored abroad – effected by anyone who resides or has a business office in Italy.  
The code guarantees that the processing of personal data must be conducted in accordance with the fundamental rights and liberties as well as the dignity of the person, with particular reference to confidentiality, personal identity and the right to protection of personal data.

**Variations and updates of the IAFSTORE Privacy Policy**

IAFSTORE may modify or simply update this site Privacy Policy, in part or completely, even owing to variations of the laws and regulations that govern this matter and protect your rights. Such variations and updates of the Privacy Policy will be notified to users on the Home Page as soon as they are introduced and will be binding as soon as published on the web site. We therefore invite you to visit this section often to read the most recent and updated version of this Privacy Policy.
